A Guide to the Papers of Norborne Berkeley 1918-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Norborne Berkeley 1918-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7667
This collection consists of about 47,000 items or 47 shelf feet.
Administrative Information
Access
The papers may be examined only by permission of Mr. Francis L. Berkeley, Jr. Papers pertaining to the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia will remain closed until opened by that body.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by Norborne Berkeley, Jr through Francis L. Berkeley on 20 August 1964. The papers arrived in file cabinets taken from Norborne Berkeley's Pennsylvania home and in storage boxes supplied by the shipping company.
Biographical/Historical Information
Norborne Berkeley was born in Danville, Virginia on 13 May 1891. After graduating from Episcopal High School in Alexandria, Virginia, he entered law school at George Washington Law School in Washington, D.C. After his first year, he transferred to the Law School of the University of Virginia, from which he graduated in 1916. While at the University, Berkeley played football and was a member of Delta Kappa Epsilon and the Eli Banana Society. Berkeley was admitted to the Virginia Bar in 1916, but went to New York to join the firm of Cravath and Henderson.
When the United States entered World War I, he left New York to become a captain in the Field Artillery of the United States Army. While in France he graduated from the General Staff College and attended Oxford University and Inns of Court. Shortly before his discharge in 1919, Berkeley was made a major. Just before leaving for his tour of duty overseas in may 1918, he married Dorothea Winslow Randolph.
Upon his discharge, Berkeley joined the legal department of Bethlehem Steel Company. In 1922 he wsa promoted to Assistant Secretary, in 1930 Assistant to the President, and in 1935 he assumed directorship of the holding company, Bethlehem Steel Corporation. He became vice-president in 1845 and retained the title until his retirement in December 1962.
Although he lived in Pennsylvania during most of his adult life, Berkeley donated both time and money to several Virginia schools. He served as a Trustee to Episcopal High School and donated a dormitory that bears his name, the organ in the chapel, and other undesignated funds. In honor of his ancestor Norborne Berkeley, Lord Botetourt, a Royal Governor of Virginia, he revived and endowed an award given at the College of William and Mary. To the University of Virginia Berkeley gave funs for athletics and the law school, as well as his time when he was appointed to the Board of Visitors in 1955. He served until the end of his term in 1963.
Berkeley is survived by a daughter Dorothea Berkeley Brush and a son Norborne, Jr.
Scope and Content Information
The papers, 1918-1964, of Norborne Berkeley consist of about 47,000 items or forty-seven shelf feet of personal, legal, business, and financial papers of his career as an executive with Bethlehem Steel Company. These include family and business correspondence, business papers, and personal investment, financial, and legal papers.
The largest group in the papers is the correspondence. Although Bethlehem Steel Company retained all correspondence that dealt strictly with the day to day business, there is a mixing of business and family material in the files. There is also a great deal of family coreespondence since Berkeley apparently preferred to dictate all letters. The files include letters and carbons of replies. In the rare instances where he wrote a letter by hand, there is generally a copy. Among the more interesting letters are those written by Berkeley to his wife during his tour of duty overseas.
Another large portion deals with Berkeley's private investments and finances. These include reports on oil and gas drilling in Kansas, Texas, Oklahoma, Louisiana, and Colorado and the sales of the raw material. Among the financial papers are check stubs, stock investment reports, trust reports and income tax returns. The rest of the collection includes material intended to be placed in scrapbooks, papers pertaining to the University of Virginia Board of Visitors, and photographs. Papers pertaining to Berkeley's affiliation with Episcopal High School have been sent to that school.
Arrangement
The papers have, in general, been kept in the original order and groups in which they were received. Therefore much of the correspondence will be found in reverse order, i.e. December 31- January 1 rahter than the usual January 1- December 31 arrangement. Whenever possible, the original labelling, chronology, and divisions have been retained. The papers are arranged in chronological order by year and in alphabetical order within the year, with the exception of Oil and Gas Investments. This group is arranged chronologically under the name of the drilling operations.
The collection is divided into five series with sub-headings when necessary. They are: Series I: General Correspondence, Boxes 1-78 Series II: Papers of the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia, Boxes 79-87 Series III: Business Papers a. Bethlehem Steel Company, Boxes 88-90 b. Oil and Gas Investments, Boxes 91-105 Series IV: Financial Papers a. Personal Accounts and Papers, Boxes 106-109 b. Checkbooks from Morgan, Guaranty, and Trust of New York, Box 110 c. Checkbooks from First National Bank of Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, Boxes 111-113 Series V: Miscellaneous a. Scrapbook Material, Boxes 114-116 b. Photographs - Storage Box
Contents List
- Series I: General Correspondence 1918-1964
  - Norborne Berkeley to Dorothea Randolph (Berkeley) Jan-Jul 1918, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Norborne Berkeley to Dorothea Berkeley 1918-1919, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between N. Berkeley and Fellow Officers 1919-1919 (Box 3)
  - Army Maps and Charts 1917-1919 (Box 3)
  - Official Army Bulletins, Papers and Orders 1918-1919 (Box 3)
  - Army Instruction Books and Reports 1917-1919 (Box 3)
  - World War I pictures taken in Europe 1918-1919 (Box 3)
  - Certificate of Honorable Discharge 1919 June 4 (Box 3)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers 1919 May 15-Dec 2 (Box 4)
  - Personal Correspondence and Notes for Memorandum 1919 Dec 3-1920 Jan 2 (Box 4)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers 1920 (Box 4)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers 1920 (Box 4)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers 1921 (Box 5)
  - University of Virginia Centennial Endowment Fund 1920-1921, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers 1922-1923, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers 1924-1927, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers 1928-1929, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Application for Admission of Norborne Berkeley to New York Bar 1917 March 23 (Box 7)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers 1919-1927 (Box 7)
    re. Entrance into Pennsylvania and New York Bars
  - Copies of License Agreements 1919-1924, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Deeds, Mortgages, Bonds, Releases, Agreements, etc. of Norborne Berkeley for Bethlehem Steel - Personal Record 1927 Aug-1929 Jan 31 (Box 8)
  - Bethlehem Community Chest Campaign - 7th Ward Team 1926-1927 (Box 8)
  - Personal Correspondence, A-B 1930-1939, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Personal Correspondence, Anne C. Berkeley 1930-1939 (Box 9)
  - Personal Correspondence, Annie H. Berkeley 1930-1939 (Box 9)
  - Personal Correspondence, Estate of Anne Harrison Berkeley 1939 (Box 9)
  - Personal Correspondence, Estate of Campbell Berkeley 1931-1932 (Box 9)
  - Personal Correspondence, Norborne Berkeley, Jr. 1930-1939 (Box 10)
  - Personal Correspondence, Landon C. Berkeley 1930-1939, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Personal Correspondence, Landon C. Berkeley 1939, Special File (Box 10)
  - Personal Correspondence, H. C. Berkeley 1930-1939 (Box 10)
  - Personal Correspondence, G. G. Berkeley 1930-1939 (Box 10)
  - Personal Correspondence, Dorothea R. Berkeley 1930-1939, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Personal Correspondence, Bethlehem Steel Co. 1930-1939 (Box 11)
    Expense Account
  - Personal Correspondence, Bethlehem Steel Co. 1930-1939 (Box 11)
    Stocks
  - Personal Correspondence, C 1930-1939 (Box 11)
  - Personal Correspondence, Chatham Hall 1934-1938 (Box 11)
  - Personal Correspondence, Camp Yonahnoka 1933-1935 (Box 11)
  - Personal Correspondence, D-E 1930-1939 (Box 11)
  - Personal Correspondence, Episcopal High School 1930-1939, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Copies of a letter from N. B. to Members of the Old Boy Association, Episcopal High School 1938 Oct 5 (Box 12)
  - Personal Papers and Correspondence, Centennial Speech at Episcopal High School 1939 Oct 14 (Box 12)
  - Catalogue of Episcopal High School and Copies of the Monthly Chronicle of the Episcopal High School 1932-1933, 1939 (Box 12)
  - Personal Correspondence, F 1930-1939 (Box 12)
  - Personal Correspondence, First National Bank of Bethlehem, Pennsylvania 1930-1939 (Box 12)
  - Personal Correspondence, G 1930-1939 (Box 13)
  - Personal Correspondence, Golf scores 1930-1939 (Box 13)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, Morgan Guaranty and Trust Co. 1930-1939 (Box 13)
  - Personal Correspondence, H 1930-1939 (Box 13)
  - Personal Correspondence, The Hartridge School 1938-1939 (Box 13)
  - Personal Correspondence, Robert T. Houk, III 1939 (Box 13)
  - Personal Correspondence, I 1930-1939 (Box 13)
  - Personal Correspondence, Insurance 1930-1939 (Box 13)
  - Personal Correspondence, Investments 1930-1939 (Box 13)
  - Personal Correspondence, J 1930-1939 (Box 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, K 1930-1938 (Box 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, Caleb S. Kennedy 1938 Oct 4 (Box 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, L 1930-1934 (Box 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, The Links Club 1939 (Box 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, M 1930-1939 (Box 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, Military Order of Foreign War of the United States 1930-1939 (Box 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, N, O, and P 1930-1939, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Personal Correspondence, R-S 1930-1939, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Personal Correspondence, Saucon Valley Country Club 1930-1939 (Box 15)
  - Personal Correspondence, Soldier's Bonus Bonds 1925-1937 (Box 15)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, Speeches ca. 1930-1939 (Box 15)
  - Personal Correspondence, Mrs. B. D. Spilman, Jr. 1933 (Box 15)
  - Personal Correspondence, T 1930-1939 (Box 15)
  - Personal Correspondence, Trinity Episcopal Church Vestry 1935-1939 (Box 15)
  - Personal Correspondence, U 1930-1939 (Box 16)
  - Personal Correspondence, University Club of New York 1930-1939 (Box 16)
  - Personal Correspondence, University of Virginia 1930-1939 (Box 16)
  - Personal Correspondence, University of Virginia 3-3-3 Athletic Council 1933-1938 (Box 16)
  - Personal Correspondence, University of Virginia Professional Ethics Exam 1938-1939 (Box 16)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, University of Virginia Professional Ethics 1938-1939 (Box 17)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, University of Virginia Alderman Alumni Fund 1937-1939 (Box 17)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, University of Virginia Alderman Alumni Fund Bulletins 1936-1939 (Box 17)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, University of Virginia Alumni Magazine 1939 (Box 17)
  - Personal Correspondence, V 1930-1939 (Box 17)
  - Personal Correspondence, Vacation 1935-1939 (Box 18)
  - Personal Correspondence, W 1930-1939 (Box 18)
  - Personal Correspondence, Wharton Weems 1937-1939 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence and Plans for songbook 1938 (Box 18)
    For Dorothea Randolph Berkeley on 20th Wedding Anniversay
  - Personal Correspondence, Y and Z 1930-1939 (Box 18)
  - Personal Correspondence, A 1940-1944 (Box 19)
  - Personal Correspondence, Appendicitics 1941 (Box 19)
  - Personal Correspondence, B 1940-1944, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Personal Correspondence, Mrs. Dorothea R. Berkeley 1940-1944 (Box 19)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, Dorothea R. Berkeley Wedding 1940 (Box 20)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, Guest List to Dorothea R. Berkeley Wedding 1940 (Box 20)
  - Personal Correspondence, Anne C. Berkeley 1940-1944 (Box 20)
  - Personal Correspondence, Berkeley general 1940-1944 (Box 20)
  - Personal Correspondence, H. C. Berkeley 1940-1944, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Personal Correspondence, Norborne Berkeley, Jr. 1940-1944 (Box 21)
  - Personal Correspondence, Norborne Berkeley, Jr 1942 (Box 21)
    re: Enlistment in Marines
  - Personal Correspondence, Landon C. Berkeley 1940-1944 (Box 21)
  - Personal Correspondence, Bethlehem Club 1940-1944 (Box 21)
  - Personal Correspondence, Bethelem Steel Company 1940-1944 (Box 21)
  - Personal Correspondence, Bethlehem Steel Company 1940-1944 (Box 21)
  - Personal Correspondence, E. D. Bransome Dinner 1944 (Box 21)
  - Personal Correspondence, C 1940-1944 (Box 21)
  - Personal Correspondence, College of William and Mary 1940-1944 (Box 22)
  - Personal Correspondence, D-E 1940-1944, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Personal Correspondence, Episcopal High School 1940-1944 (Box 22)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, The Monthly Chronicle of Episcopal High School 1940-1943 (Box 22)
  - Personal Correspondence, F 1940-1944 (Box 23)
  - Personal Correspondence, First National Bank and Trust Company and Bethlehem, Pennsylvania 1940-1944 (Box 23)
  - Personal Correspondence, G 1940-1944 (Box 23)
  - Personal Correspondence, Guranty Trust Company 1940-1944 (Box 23)
  - Personal Correspondence, H 1940-1944 (Box 23)
  - Personal Correspondence, C. R. Holton receipts 1940-1944 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, Robert T. Houk, III 1940-1944 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, Mrs. Robert T. Houk, III 1940-1944 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, I 1940-1944 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, Insurance 1940-1944 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, Insurance receipts 1940-1944 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, Investments 1940-1944 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, J-K 1940-1944, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, Alden Kimball Estate 1944 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, L 1940-1944 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, Lawsuit, Alcy Cwerdinski 1941 (Box 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, The Links 1940-1944 (Box 25)
  - Personal Correspondence, M 1940-1944 (Box 25)
  - Personal Correspondence, Membership and License cards 1940-1944 (Box 25)
  - Personal Correspondence, Military Order of Foreign Wars of the United States 1940-1944 (Box 25)
  - Personal Correspondence, N- O-P 1940-1944, 3 folders (Box 25)
  - Personal Correspondence, Pine Valley Golf Club 1940-1944 (Box 25)
  - Personal Correspondence, R-S 1940-1944, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Personal Correspondence, Saucon Valley Country Club and Saucon Valley Country Club Receipts 1940-1944, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Personal Correspondence, T 1940-1944 (Box 26)
  - Personal Correspondence, Tax Receipts 1940-1944 (Box 26)
  - Personal Correspondence, Traveler's Insurance Claim for Norborne Berkeley, Jr. 1943 (Box 26)
  - Personal Correspondence, Trinity Episcopal Church 1940-1944 (Box 26)
  - Personal Correspondence, Trinity Episcopal Church 1940-1944 (Box 27)
    Financial Statements
  - Personal Correspondence, Trinity Episcopal Church 1940-1944 (Box 27)
    re: Building Loans
  - Personal Correspondence, U 1940-1944 (Box 27)
  - Personal Correspondence, US Army 80th Division 1940-1944 (Box 27)
  - Personal Correspondence, University Club, NY 1940-1944 (Box 27)
  - Personal Correspondence, University of Virginia 1940-1944 (Box 27)
  - Personal Correspondence, University of Virginia Alderman Alumni Fund 1940-1944 (Box 27)
  - Personal Correspondence, V 1940-1944 (Box 28)
  - Personal Correspondence, Vacation 1940-1944 (Box 28)
  - Personal Correspondence, W 1940-1944 (Box 28)
  - Personal Correspondence, Wharton Weems 1940-1944 (Box 28)
  - Personal Correspondence, Y 1940-1944 (Box 28)
  - Personal Correspondence, Yale University 1940-1944 (Box 28)
  - Personal Correspondence, Z 1942 (Box 28)
  - Personal Correspondence, A 1945-1949 (Box 28)
  - Personal Correspondence, B 1945-1949 (Box 29)
  - Berkeley Family Correspondence 1945-1949 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence with Anne C. Berkeley 1945-1949 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence with Harrison C. Berkeley 1945-1949 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence with Landon C. Berkeley 1945-1949 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence with Norborne Berkeley, Jr. 1945-1949 (Box 29)
  - Copy of Discharge Papers, Yale Degree and Law Degree for Norborne Berkeley, Jr. 1945-1949 (Box 30)
  - Bethlehem Club 1945-1949 (Box 30)
  - Bethlehem Steel Club 1946-1949 (Box 30)
  - Bethlehem Steel Company, Board of Directors and Stock Information 1945-1949 (Box 30)
  - Personal Correspondence, C 1945-1949 (Box 30)
  - College and William and Mary 1945-1949 (Box 30)
    Re: Botetourt Medal
  - Personal Correspondence, D-E 1945-1949, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - T he Monthly Chronicle of Episcopal High School 1945-1949 (Box 31)
  - Personal Correpsondence, F 1945-1949 (Box 31)
  - Farmington Country Club 1945-1949 (Box 31)
  - First National Bank of Bethlehem, Pennsylvania 1945-1949 (Box 31)
  - Personal Correspondence, G 1945-1949 (Box 32)
  - Guaranty Trust Company of New York 1945-1949 (Box 32)
  - Personal Correspondence, H 1945-1949 (Box 32)
  - Harvard law School 1945-1947 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence with Robert T. Houk, III 1945-1948 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence with Mrs. Robert T. Houk, III 1945-1949 (Box 32)
  - House, New Caanan, Conn., (Occupied by Mr. and Mrs. Robert T. Houk, III 1945-1949 (Box 32)
  - House, "Stonesthrow" 1949-1950 (Box 33)
  - House located at 1318 Prospect Avenue 1924-1949 (Box 33)
  - Personal Correspondence, I 1945-1949 (Box 33)
  - Insurance 1945-1949 (Box 33)
  - Insurance receipts 1945-1949 (Box 33)
  - Personal Correspondence, J - K - L 1945-1949, 3 folders (Box 33)
  - The Links Golf Club 1945-1949 (Box 34)
  - Personal Correspondence, M 1945-1949 (Box 34)
  - Membership Cards and License Plates Number 1949-1950 (Box 34)
  - Metropolitan Club 1946-1949 (Box 34)
  - John L. Morehead 1946-1949 (Box 35)
  - Personal Correspondence, N - O - P 1945-1949, 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Pine Valley Golf Club 1945-1949 (Box 35)
  - Personal Correspondence, R 1945-1949 (Box 35)
  - Personal Correspondence, S 1945-1949 (Box 36)
  - Saucon Valley Country Club and Causon Valley Country Club Receipts 1945-1949, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Personal Correspondence, T 1945-1949 (Box 36)
  - Tax Receipts 1945-1949 (Box 36)
  - Trinity Episcopal Church, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania 1945-1949 (Box 36)
  - United States Army, 313th Artillery 1945-1949 (Box 36)
  - University Club, New York 1945-1949 (Box 37)
  - University of Virginia 1945-1948 (Box 37)
  - University of Virginia, Development Fund 1947-1948 (Box 37)
  - University of Virginia, Alderman and Alumni Fund 1945-1948 (Box 37)
  - Correspondence and Papers 1946-1949 (Box 38)
    Re: Norborne Berkeley, Jr's entry and placement at the U. Va. Law School
  - Reports of the University of Virginia Law School Association, the University of Virginia Record Law Department and the Program of Graduation, 1949 1941-1949 (Box 38)
  - Personal Correspondence, V 1945-1949 (Box 38)
  - Vacation File 1945-1949 (Box 38)
  - Personal Correspondence, W 1945-1949 (Box 38)
  - Personal Correspondence, Y 1945-1949 (Box 39)
  - Personal Correspondence, Z 1948-1949 (Box 39)
  - Personal Correspondence, A 1950-1954 (Box 39)
  - Personal Correspondence, B 1950-1954, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Personal Correspondence, Dorothea R. Berkeley 1950-1954 (Box 39)
  - Personal Correspondence, Berkeley General 1950-1954 (Box 39)
  - Personal Correspondence, Anne C. Berkeley 1950-1954 (Box 40)
  - Personal Correspondence, H. C. Berkeley 1950-1954 (Box 40)
  - Personal Correspondence, Landon C. Berkeley 1950-1954 (Box 40)
  - Personal Correspondence, Norborne Berkeley, Jr. 1950-1954 (Box 40)
  - Personal Correspondence, Norborne Berkeley, Jr Wedding 1950-1954 (Box 40)
  - Personal Correspondence, Mrs. Norborne Berkeley, Jr 1951 (Box 40)
  - Personal Correspondence, Bethlehem Club 1950-1954 (Box 40)
  - Personal Correspondence, Bethlehem Steel Club 1950-1954, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Personal Correspondence, Bethlehem Steel Company Expense Account 1950-1954 (Box 41)
  - Personal Correspondence, C 1950-1954 (Box 41)
  - Personal Correspondence, Carlton House 1950-1954 (Box 41)
  - Personal Correspondence, Clippings 1950-1954 (Box 41)
  - Personal Correspondence, College of William and Mary 1950-1954 (Box 41)
  - Personal Correspondence, Contributions 1950-1954 (Box 41)
  - Personal Correspondence, D 1950-1954 (Box 41)
  - Personal Correspondence, DKE 1950-1954 (Box 41)
  - Personal Papers and Correspondence, Diet Lists 1950-1954 (Box 42)
  - Personal Correspondence, E 1950-1954 (Box 42)
  - Personal Correspondence, Episcopal High School 1950-1954, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Personal Correspondence, Reports of Episcopal High School 1950-1954 (Box 42)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, Speech to the Graduating Class at Episcopal High School 1954 March 27 (Box 43)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, Catalogues of Episcopal High School and Directory of Living Old Boys of Episcopal High School 1950-1954 (Box 43)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, The Monthly Chronicle of Episcopal High School 1950-1954 (Box 43)
  - Personal Correspondence, F 1950-1954 (Box 43)
  - Farmington Country Club 1950-1954 (Box 43)
  - Personal Correspondence, First National Bank and Trust Company, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania 1950-1954 (Box 43)
  - Personal Correspondence, Fuel Oil 1950-1954 (Box 44)
  - Personal Correspondence, G 1950-1954 (Box 44)
  - Personal Correspondence, Girard Trust Company 1950-1953 (Box 44)
  - Personal Correspondence, Guaranty Trust Company 1950-1954 (Box 44)
  - Personal Correspondence, H 1950-1954 (Box 44)
  - Personal Correspondence, H 1950-1954 (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence, Robert T. Houk, III 1950-1954 (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence, Mrs. Robert T. Houk, III 1950-1954 (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, House "Stonesthrow" 1950-1954 (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, House, Frey Property 1950-1954 (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, House, Reiss property 1950-1954 (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence, I 1950-1954 (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence, Insurance Receipts 1950-1954 (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence, Insurance 1950-1954 (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence, J- K 1950-1954, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Personal Correspondence, L 1950-1954 (Box 46)
  - Personal Correspondence, The Links 1950-1954 (Box 46)
  - Personal Correspondence, M 1950-1954 (Box 46)
  - Personal Correspondence, Metropolitan Club 1950-1954 (Box 46)
  - Personal Correspondence, Military Order Foreign Wars of the United States 1950-1954 (Box 46)
  - Personal Correspondence, John L. Morehead 1950-1954 (Box 46)
  - Personal Correspondence, N - O - P 1950-1954, 3 folders (Box 47)
  - Personal Correspondence, Party 1950-1954 (Box 47)
  - Personal Correspondence, Pine Valley Golf Club 1950-1954 (Box 47)
  - Personal Correspondence, Philadelphia Inquirer 1950 (Box 47)
  - Personal Correspondence, Powers of Attorney 1950-1954 (Box 47)
  - Personal Correspondence, Q - R 1950-1954, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Personal Correspondence, S 1950-1954 (Box 48)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, Saucon Valley Country Club USGA Amateur Championship Golf Tournament 1950-'951, 3 folders (Box 48)
  - Personal Correspondence and Papers, Saucon Valley Country Club USGA Amateur Championship Golf Tournament 1951, 4 folders (Box 49)
  - Personal Correspondence, Saucon Valley Country Club 1950-1954, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Personal Correspondence, Scudder, Stevens and Clark 1950-1954 (Box 50)
  - Personal Correspondence, T 1950-1954 (Box 50)
  - Personal Correspondence, Tax Receipts 1950-1954 (Box 50)